<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>journals on Adam&#39;s Blog.</title>
    <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/category/journals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in journals on Adam&#39;s Blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adamliu.io/blog/category/journals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting On Anthony Bourdain</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/reflecting-on-anthony-bourdain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/reflecting-on-anthony-bourdain/</guid>
      <description>I just watched the Tony Bourdain documentary Roadrunner: A Film About Anthony Bourdain yesterday. It&#39;s great. It&#39;s emotional. And it makes you sad.
It made me miss this guy who I didn&#39;t even watch any of his shows when he was alive.
Before watching it, I just finished binge watching Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown, his 12 season long travel show, and it is FUCKING GREAT!
Getting to know Tony through the screen I&#39;ve always known about Tony, a famous chef who was making travel documentaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Boat Life Is My Ultimate Goal?</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-the-boat-life-is-my-ultimate-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-the-boat-life-is-my-ultimate-goal/</guid>
      <description>We are all wanderers, and we are all survivors.
 We are all trying to build a better future for ourselves. We go to school, go to college, get jobs to make a living, try to get promoted, fall in love with the people that we think is right for us, give birth to babies to carry our hopes and dreams and love, and we do our best to provide everything for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future Of My Life</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-future-of-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-future-of-my-life/</guid>
      <description>As I&#39;m writing this (2nd of Dec, 2020), I&#39;ve been back in China from Australia for 2 years already.
My view on the future of my life has changed from what I wanted when I was back in Australia, where I spent almost 4 years there, the part of the world I&#39;d loved every single second I spent in.
My eyes started to open to understand more of the world not long after I arrive in Melbourne, since I started reading English books (Does it mean I was small minded before Australia?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Beautiful Future</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beautiful-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beautiful-future/</guid>
      <description>What would my future be like? Where would I be? What would I be doing?
 It&#39;s Sep. 2020. I&#39;m 1 month away from my 30th birthday, and I&#39;m still asking myself this question.
Does it mean that I&#39;m a loser? Maybe. Everyone has their own judgement.
I was born Chinese, and there&#39;s a traditional Chinese saying goes like: &amp;ldquo;三十而立&amp;rdquo;. Which means, when you are 30, you should be fully independent by yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/journals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>