<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on Adam&#39;s Blog.</title>
    <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on Adam&#39;s Blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adamliu.io/blog/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Animal Nature</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/our-animal-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/our-animal-nature/</guid>
      <description>I just came across this post on Instagram, it&#39;s a animal sacrifice ceremony in Nepal.

This is not unprecedented, this kind of activities have been around for thousands of years. What&#39;s unprecedented is the calling out for this kind of activities. This is a very weird dynamic.
On one hand, I truly believe that there&#39;s nothing good about animal cruelty, cruelty wouldn&#39;t lift a person&#39;s spirits, but rather, it can suck people into dark abysses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Industrialised Humans</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-industrialised-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-industrialised-humans/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always found it weird that how much of our identities are defined by what we do. And this phenomenon has extended beyond workplaces. Imagine a casual convo at a party when one meets new people:
 &amp;ldquo;So John, what do you do for a living?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Uhh, I&#39;m a ### / Uhh, I do ###, and you?.&amp;rdquo;  Of course not every convo is like this, but surprisingly a lot of the convos would touch on this point at the early stage when people socialise with strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Game Is Stupid</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-power-game-is-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-power-game-is-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I love the show Billions, the story is so great that I binge watched pretty much every season.
But here&#39;s the thing, even I loved the story, doesn&#39;t mean that I think that there&#39;s much value to the fact Bobby Axelrod &amp;amp; Chuck Rhoades are always fucking with each other just because they are in the habit of winning and whatever each of them did, bred hatred towards each other. (Btw did the writer named them to sound like kids intentionally?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Fast, Not Slow</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/build-fast-not-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/build-fast-not-slow/</guid>
      <description>Be Impatient With Actions, Be Patience With The Results.
 Patience is a misunderstood word. In my opinion, it has been associated with mediocrity, or at least has been used as an excuse for mediocrity.
Because people are patient, the business they want to start should wait, the book they want to read can wait, the gym can wait, the trip can wait. Because they are patient, they can always spend time with their kids when they retire&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/compound-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/compound-interest/</guid>
      <description>Compounding is easy to understand, but easy to underestimate &amp;amp; forget about as well, because it’s not intuitive, even for smart people. Michael Batnick once explained it:
 If I ask you to calculate 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 in your head, you can do it in a few seconds (it’s 72). If I ask you to calculate 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8, your head will explode (it’s 134,217,728).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas And Execution</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/ideas-and-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/ideas-and-execution/</guid>
      <description>The Pawn: Idea (Multipliers)
 Awful idea = -1 Weak idea = 1 So-so idea = 5 Good idea = 25 Great idea = 100 Brilliant idea = 1000  The King: Execution (Accelerator Pressure)
 No execution = $1 Weak execution = $1,000 So-so execution = $10,000 Good execution = $100,000 Great execution = $1,000,000 Brilliant execution = $10,000,000  Those who say &amp;ldquo;execution is king and ideas are shit&amp;rdquo;, can be described as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Predators</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/think-like-predators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/think-like-predators/</guid>
      <description>If you watch any wildlife documentary, it&#39;s common that most predators are not on the hunt all the time, let it be lions, tigers, eagles, sharks, etc. Most of the time, they are resting, and playing around.
But on the contrary, ruminants are always eating, or always &amp;ldquo;chewing the cud&amp;rdquo;, in order to have consume the sufficient amount of energy to survive. And these hard working animals are always preyed upon by predators, no exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/thoughts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Working Way Too Much</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-working-way-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-working-way-too-much/</guid>
      <description>As humans, we simply work too much. In my opinion, most people have become the [[The industrialised humans]]. Most of us work like machines and this way of working has been widely accepted as a social norm. Because the societies around the globe have been measuring the quality of the livelihood by GDP for decades, productivity has become the one thing different countries and cities chase after.
In most western countries, people work the standard 9-to-5 days up to 40 hours per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Like Lions, Not Like Gazelles</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/work-like-lions-not-like-gazelles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/work-like-lions-not-like-gazelles/</guid>
      <description>This idea is closely related to [[Think Like Predators]], and it&#39;s the opposite to the widely accepted social norm: [[We Are Working Way Too Much]].
The money we earn, and the quality of our lives is not defined by the intensity and the hours we work, but rather, it&#39;s defined by the value we provide.
And Value increases &amp;amp; decreases in an exponential manner, not in a linear manner.
If you can provide great value, you should still be rewarded handsomely even if you don&#39;t work for a second.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>