<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wealth on Adam&#39;s Blog.</title>
    <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/tags/wealth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wealth on Adam&#39;s Blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adamliu.io/blog/tags/wealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It sucks to be poor</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/it-sucks-to-be-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/it-sucks-to-be-poor/</guid>
      <description>It really sucks to be poor.
 You see it everywhere. On the street, in the news of 3rd world countries, even in the classrooms. When you don&#39;t have money, everything you do and think of is about making the next paycheck, putting the next meal on the table, and maybe winning the lottery so you can have a good life just as the people you envy. There&#39;s a study showing that parents even talk to their kids less when money is tight, while all a kid needs is attention &amp;amp; love from parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build Wealth</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-build-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-build-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is The Abundance of Value Wealth is the abundance of valuable things, including [[Money]], but way beyond money.
Wealth starts from money  Money doesn&#39;t solve all your problems, but it solves all your money problems.
 To most people, wealth is only about money, while it&#39;s a limited view, it has it&#39;s reasons. In a human world, [[Wealth Is Built Upon Money]]. So understanding [[The Pursuit Of Money]] (How To Make Money) is important, and understanding money is not everything is also important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/money/</guid>
      <description>Money has many faces. It is Power. It&#39;s Energy. And [[Money Is The Glue of Society]].
It&#39;s not evil, it&#39;s does not discriminate, it&#39;s the most just equalizer in the world.
Money is not chased after, it&#39;s not made:
 It&#39;s attracted.
 As contradictory as it may sound, [[The Pursuit Of Money]] is actually a spiritual journey (spirituality can be both constructive &amp;amp; destructive). It helps us establishing our personalities (good or evil), our worldview (big or small, comprehensive or narrow), our value (noble or unimpressive).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wealthy Mind</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-wealthy-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-wealthy-mind/</guid>
      <description>The wealthy mind is very different from the working mind. And here&#39;s a list of the differences.
[[Compound Interest]] is a close association of wealth creation. However, it&#39;s often threw around when people use Warren Buffett as a case study, or used by money-making gurus when they are trying to sell courses, but rarely implemented by most people, including these gurus&amp;rsquo; devotees.
[[Work Like Lions, Not Like Gazelles]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealth</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is extremely important, and not very well understood. In my opinion, it&#39;s something we all should strive for.
 YOU HAVE TO BE RICH!
 To put it simply: most problems most people have, are money problems. [[It sucks to be poor]].
But I truly believe, that everyone can be rich!
People understand wealth differently. To some, a person who&#39;s making $100,000 a year (in 2020) is considered rich, a giant house (without considering the mortgage and the house owner&#39;s ability to pay it back) represents wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealthy People&#39;s Definition of Rich</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealthy-people-s-definition-of-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealthy-people-s-definition-of-rich/</guid>
      <description>What&#39;s your definition of Rich?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>