<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi on Adam&#39;s Blog.</title>
    <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi on Adam&#39;s Blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adamliu.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Animal Nature</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/our-animal-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/our-animal-nature/</guid>
      <description>I just came across this post on Instagram, it&#39;s a animal sacrifice ceremony in Nepal.

This is not unprecedented, this kind of activities have been around for thousands of years. What&#39;s unprecedented is the calling out for this kind of activities. This is a very weird dynamic.
On one hand, I truly believe that there&#39;s nothing good about animal cruelty, cruelty wouldn&#39;t lift a person&#39;s spirits, but rather, it can suck people into dark abysses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting On Anthony Bourdain</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/reflecting-on-anthony-bourdain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/reflecting-on-anthony-bourdain/</guid>
      <description>I just watched the Tony Bourdain documentary Roadrunner: A Film About Anthony Bourdain yesterday. It&#39;s great. It&#39;s emotional. And it makes you sad.
It made me miss this guy who I didn&#39;t even watch any of his shows when he was alive.
Before watching it, I just finished binge watching Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown, his 12 season long travel show, and it is FUCKING GREAT!
Getting to know Tony through the screen I&#39;ve always known about Tony, a famous chef who was making travel documentaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Industrialised Humans</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-industrialised-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-industrialised-humans/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always found it weird that how much of our identities are defined by what we do. And this phenomenon has extended beyond workplaces. Imagine a casual convo at a party when one meets new people:
 &amp;ldquo;So John, what do you do for a living?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Uhh, I&#39;m a ### / Uhh, I do ###, and you?.&amp;rdquo;  Of course not every convo is like this, but surprisingly a lot of the convos would touch on this point at the early stage when people socialise with strangers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A life with no drama</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/a-life-with-no-drama/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/a-life-with-no-drama/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always been curious about how efficient would this world be if there&#39;s no unnecessary drama happening in people&#39;s lives. Fighting, lying, cheating, etc. Of course without them life would be pretty boring, but efficiency is boring, but it&#39;s a better type of boring than getting stuck in the traffic jam on your way to work type of boring.
But efficiency frees you up, for you to explore interesting things that would give you new experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding the negative human &amp; environmental impact</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/avoiding-the-negative-human-environmental-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/avoiding-the-negative-human-environmental-impact/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m scared of climate change, not only because it will bring significant change to our lives, but also because the reason we are only starting to take it seriously now (2021), is because climate change is not only a climate issue, a significant part of it is the human politics. That&#39;s why I said &amp;ldquo;human &amp;amp; environmental impact&amp;rdquo;. Now, I have no power to help in any aspect in terms of climate change on a big scale as an individual at the moment, while I do want to build my businesses asap and make sure I have enough time and money to help reducing climate change, I also want to have the safest way of life for my family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Freedom: The Freedom To Think</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/mental-freedom-the-freedom-to-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/mental-freedom-the-freedom-to-think/</guid>
      <description>One&#39;s mental freedom is not much from their [[Physical Freedom: Being Able To Move]]. While living in Australia gave me much calmer mental states, it&#39;s not enough. The human mind has huge potentials that most people have never taken full advantage of, and in my opinion the main reasons for that is because we are not exposed to enough new ideas, new cultures, and new perspectives.
Ultimately, the point of having physical freedom is to free our minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peace Of Mind: The Inner Peace We All Need</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/peace-of-mind-the-inner-peace-we-all-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/peace-of-mind-the-inner-peace-we-all-need/</guid>
      <description>Having a place to think is extremely important.
Monks find their peace through meditation in temples, and they would practice it for their entire life, which is something most regular people are not able to do.
But maybe it&#39;s not that necessary for every single one of us to go to the extremes only a few masters can achieve. Maybe the point of them reaching the pinnacle of enlightenment, is to point the rest of us to the direction that works, so we can save our own sanities from the chaos of the human world we live in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Need To Travel More Meaningfully</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/people-need-to-travel-more-meaningfully/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/people-need-to-travel-more-meaningfully/</guid>
      <description>One of the undesired consequences of the booming of the travel industry is the huge increase of carbon emission, and the destruction of the beauty of the tourist attractions. Instead of enjoying the beauty of historical sites &amp;amp; local cultures, traveling for most people have become a money spending &amp;amp; photo taking journey so they can go back and show their friends where they&#39;ve been, as well as enjoying a day of two of the life they saw in movies, sipping on apple martini by the pool in a resort compound, posing in front of the Eiffel Tower, shit like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Freedom: Being Able To Move</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/physical-freedom-being-able-to-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/physical-freedom-being-able-to-move/</guid>
      <description>While the modern society has improved our quality of life, we&#39;ve also sacrificed our sanity. In my opinion, most of the mental issues people experience, including hatred, anxiety, hopelessness, are all caused by the changes to the human society that we call &amp;ldquo;advancements&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;progress&amp;quot;.
It&#39;s simply because these &amp;ldquo;advancements&amp;rdquo; stripped away most of our physical freedom, as well as our [[Mental Freedom: the freedom to think]].
For instance, megacities are the best representations of human advancements, big money flow through them, big dreams are made within these concrete jungles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be Flexible And Stable At The Same Time</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/to-be-flexible-and-stable-at-the-same-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/to-be-flexible-and-stable-at-the-same-time/</guid>
      <description>As homo sapiens, our need for traveling to &amp;amp; exploring different places have never be different from our ancestors, that&#39;s why the travel industry was booming before COVID-19 hit, that&#39;s also why &amp;ldquo;getting away&amp;rdquo; always sounds so good to most people.
But on the other hand, we also look for stability in life, we are all longing for a place safe from all dangers, a place we can stay at and enjoy life, this is also the reason our ancestors settled down and started growing agriculture, which is a very hard thing to do back then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Boat Life Is My Ultimate Goal?</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-the-boat-life-is-my-ultimate-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-the-boat-life-is-my-ultimate-goal/</guid>
      <description>We are all wanderers, and we are all survivors.
 We are all trying to build a better future for ourselves. We go to school, go to college, get jobs to make a living, try to get promoted, fall in love with the people that we think is right for us, give birth to babies to carry our hopes and dreams and love, and we do our best to provide everything for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power Game Is Stupid</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-power-game-is-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-power-game-is-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I love the show Billions, the story is so great that I binge watched pretty much every season.
But here&#39;s the thing, even I loved the story, doesn&#39;t mean that I think that there&#39;s much value to the fact Bobby Axelrod &amp;amp; Chuck Rhoades are always fucking with each other just because they are in the habit of winning and whatever each of them did, bred hatred towards each other. (Btw did the writer named them to sound like kids intentionally?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/mission/</guid>
      <description>The more I think about it, the more I feel the earth is Fucked.
Climate change, plastic overuse, massive industrial pollution&amp;hellip; I don&#39;t think I need to keep listing, and just do a bit of Googling you&#39;ll find the stats to support these claims.
If you only like money, or like whatever seems fancy or luxurious, or you&#39;re simply too busy getting through your everyday life, and you don&#39;t know how good a better environment can make you feel both mentally &amp;amp; physically, these environmental concerns wouldn&#39;t bother you that much, and the people who are calling for change and protesting would seem crazy to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future Of My Life</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-future-of-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-future-of-my-life/</guid>
      <description>As I&#39;m writing this (2nd of Dec, 2020), I&#39;ve been back in China from Australia for 2 years already.
My view on the future of my life has changed from what I wanted when I was back in Australia, where I spent almost 4 years there, the part of the world I&#39;d loved every single second I spent in.
My eyes started to open to understand more of the world not long after I arrive in Melbourne, since I started reading English books (Does it mean I was small minded before Australia?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi.</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/hi/</guid>
      <description>* It&#39;s better to view this site on desktop, because with every inter-page you click on, you create a sequence of pages, in some ways, this sequence can be your own unique experience of reading my blog. ;)I&#39;m Adam, I&#39;m on a [[Mission]], and this is a representation of part of my mind. And I think through them, you can find all these scattered thoughts representing [[My Beliefs]] one way or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Beautiful Future</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beautiful-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beautiful-future/</guid>
      <description>What would my future be like? Where would I be? What would I be doing?
 It&#39;s Sep. 2020. I&#39;m 1 month away from my 30th birthday, and I&#39;m still asking myself this question.
Does it mean that I&#39;m a loser? Maybe. Everyone has their own judgement.
I was born Chinese, and there&#39;s a traditional Chinese saying goes like: &amp;ldquo;三十而立&amp;rdquo;. Which means, when you are 30, you should be fully independent by yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Gates Insisted on Having 1 Year Runway</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/bill-gates-insisted-on-having-1-year-runway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/bill-gates-insisted-on-having-1-year-runway/</guid>
      <description>From the day Bill Gates started Microsoft, he insisted on always having enough cash in the bank to keep the company alive for 12 months with no revenue coming in.
In 1995 he was asked by Charlie Rose why he kept so much cash on hand. “Things change so fast in technology that next year’s business wasn’t guaranteed”, he said, “Including Microsoft’s.”
In 2007 he reflected:
“I was always worried because people who worked for me were older than me and had kids, and I always thought, ‘What if we don’t get paid, will I be able to meet the payroll?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Fast, Not Slow</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/build-fast-not-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/build-fast-not-slow/</guid>
      <description>Be Impatient With Actions, Be Patience With The Results.
 Patience is a misunderstood word. In my opinion, it has been associated with mediocrity, or at least has been used as an excuse for mediocrity.
Because people are patient, the business they want to start should wait, the book they want to read can wait, the gym can wait, the trip can wait. Because they are patient, they can always spend time with their kids when they retire&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/compound-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/compound-interest/</guid>
      <description>Compounding is easy to understand, but easy to underestimate &amp;amp; forget about as well, because it’s not intuitive, even for smart people. Michael Batnick once explained it:
 If I ask you to calculate 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 + 8 in your head, you can do it in a few seconds (it’s 72). If I ask you to calculate 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8 x 8, your head will explode (it’s 134,217,728).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entropy</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/entropy/</guid>
      <description>Entropy works as a kind of engine for complexity. Increasing entropy, is absolutely essential to emergent complexity sans divine intervention.
 https://www.wired.com/2017/03/can-digital-simulations-reveal-rules-emergent-behavior/
entropy sets particles to “wiggling,” and they have a tendency to want to maximize their individual “wiggle room” as it were. This can drive them into a structure that winds up being complex, when seen as a whole.
This is not only true of particles at the atomic and subatomic levels, but of much more visible phenomena such as the beautiful patterns seen as a flock of starlings gathers in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraterrestrial Civilizations Don&#39;t Want To Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/extraterrestrial-civilizations-don-t-want-to-contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/extraterrestrial-civilizations-don-t-want-to-contact-us/</guid>
      <description>The Mediocrity Principle states:&amp;ldquo;if an item is drawn at random from one of several sets or categories, it&#39;s likelier to come from the most numerous category than from any one of the less numerous categories&amp;rdquo;.
Following this logic, there&#39;s nothing special about us, as well as anything we are aware of: our intelligence, civilisation, planet, galaxy, etc, unless it&#39;s proven otherwise.
Our technologies are extremely primitive when compared to the tech that the theorised Type II &amp;amp; Type III civilisations ([[Kardashev scale]]) might have, which allow us to see only the neighbouring parts of the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Filter</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s something that prevents non-living matter from becoming life (abiogenesis) and then eventually turn into Type III intelligence on the Kardashev Scale. This &amp;ldquo;something&amp;rdquo; is the stage that would make it almost impossible for any kind of life to proceed beyond it.
The Great Filter theory is a possible explanation to the Fermi Paradox: [[Where Are the Aliens?]].
But where is the Great Filter?
Maybe the great filter is [[Great Filter Theory: The Formation Of Life Itself]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Filter Theory: The Formation Of Life Itself</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-the-formation-of-life-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-the-formation-of-life-itself/</guid>
      <description>Life only began (3.5 billion years ago) after around 1 billion years later after the earth was formed, which took 10 billion years after the universe was formed (about 13.8 billion years ago when the Big Bang banged), which means the happening of life is extremely rare, not to even mention for life to evolve into our level of intelligence.
The formation of life has gone through many stages, the simplified version for this context is this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Filter Theory: We Are One Of The First</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-we-are-one-of-the-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-we-are-one-of-the-first/</guid>
      <description>We are the only intelligent life form, or we are amongst other intelligent life forms that have appeared in the universe since the creation of the universe so far and are evolving towards super-intelligence.
The universe itself is relatively young, it&#39;s assumed to be 13.6 billion years old, and suggested to last for around 200 billion years (I still need to do more research on that), so on a 100-year lifespan scale, the universe is only 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Filter Theory: We Are Yet To Extinct</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-we-are-yet-to-extinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/great-filter-theory-we-are-yet-to-extinct/</guid>
      <description>If we are not a rare instance of life in the universe, and we haven&#39;t found any sign of extraterrestrial life in the universe even the universe has existed for 13.6 billion years, maybe it&#39;s becasue there&#39;s some kind of natural event that happens in the universe that prevents life moving forward after it reaches certan level of development. Which means, we are yet to experience some kind of extinction event in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Build Wealth</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-build-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-build-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is The Abundance of Value Wealth is the abundance of valuable things, including [[Money]], but way beyond money.
Wealth starts from money  Money doesn&#39;t solve all your problems, but it solves all your money problems.
 To most people, wealth is only about money, while it&#39;s a limited view, it has it&#39;s reasons. In a human world, [[Wealth Is Built Upon Money]]. So understanding [[The Pursuit Of Money]] (How To Make Money) is important, and understanding money is not everything is also important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/how-to-make-money/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas And Execution</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/ideas-and-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/ideas-and-execution/</guid>
      <description>The Pawn: Idea (Multipliers)
 Awful idea = -1 Weak idea = 1 So-so idea = 5 Good idea = 25 Great idea = 100 Brilliant idea = 1000  The King: Execution (Accelerator Pressure)
 No execution = $1 Weak execution = $1,000 So-so execution = $10,000 Good execution = $100,000 Great execution = $1,000,000 Brilliant execution = $10,000,000  Those who say &amp;ldquo;execution is king and ideas are shit&amp;rdquo;, can be described as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/journals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kardashev scale</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/kardashev-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/kardashev-scale/</guid>
      <description>Categories of Civilizations:  Type I (planetary civilization): is able to fully utilise the energy of their home planet. Type II (stellar civilization): is able to fully utilise the energy of their star and planetary system. Type III (galactic civilization): is able to fully utilise the energy of its host galaxy.  2 More Extended Categories: Type IV (universal civilization): is able to fully utilise the energy of multiple galaxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/money/</guid>
      <description>Money has many faces. It is Power. It&#39;s Energy. And [[Money Is The Glue of Society]].
It&#39;s not evil, it&#39;s does not discriminate, it&#39;s the most just equalizer in the world.
Money is not chased after, it&#39;s not made:
 It&#39;s attracted.
 As contradictory as it may sound, [[The Pursuit Of Money]] is actually a spiritual journey (spirituality can be both constructive &amp;amp; destructive). It helps us establishing our personalities (good or evil), our worldview (big or small, comprehensive or narrow), our value (noble or unimpressive).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Is The Glue of Society</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/money-is-the-glue-of-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/money-is-the-glue-of-society/</guid>
      <description>The human world has become so specific. People are customed to choose one thing as their main focus in life and call it career, and we rarely produce anything else outside our career. Then how is it possible that we can have many things in life beside what we produce?
 Money.
 Because of the existance of money, we are able to receive money for what we&#39;ve produced, and use money to purchase what we need &amp;amp; want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/my-beliefs/</guid>
      <description>LOVE, CREATE, EXPERIENCE.
 No matter what, LOVE is the most powerful drive to lift us up, CREATE is the only way to build a better future, and only when you&#39;ve EXPERIENCEd enough, you&#39;d be able to appreciate how beautiful the world is, and understand why we should do our best to protect the good, and fight the evil.
My Rules My way of respecting people is by:
 Saying what I really think Trying my best to be most efficient so that I don&#39;t waste anyone&#39;s time, as well as my own time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number of Planets That Possibly Have Life</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/number-of-planets-that-possibly-have-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/number-of-planets-that-possibly-have-life/</guid>
      <description>The number of stars in our galaxy is around 100 – 400 billion, there are roughly an equal number of galaxies in the observable universe, so for every star in the colossal Milky Way, there’s a whole galaxy out there. All together, that comes out to the typically quoted range of between 1022 and 1024 total stars, which means that for every grain of sand on every beach on Earth, there are 10,000 stars out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/save-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/save-money/</guid>
      <description>Saving money doesn&#39;t make you a loser, but rather, it prepares you for unforeseen events in the future that require money to deal with.
Even [[Bill Gates Insisted on Having 1 Year Runway]] for Microsoft to deal with the uncertainties in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Doesn&#39;t Prove Anything</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/science-doesn-t-prove-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/science-doesn-t-prove-anything/</guid>
      <description>The history of science is the history of invalidating what we got wrong before. And our ability to invalidate previous beliefs &amp;amp; theories is from our updated understanding of the world. In science nothing is perfectly right or wrong, only &amp;ldquo;it&#39;s not invalidated yet&amp;rdquo;.
Use physics as an example.
Physics is helpful but it does not prove anything, even the most basic concepts. Theoretical models are mathematical constructs which, together with the postulates of the theory, fit data and predict new behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pursuit Of Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-pursuit-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-pursuit-of-money/</guid>
      <description>Never Chase After Money Money is a servant, you have to be the master of it. Use it, control it, but don&#39;t bow to it and be the servant of it, because it won&#39;t treat you as a servant, but a slave.
Attract Money Money can not be chased after, but it can be attracted to you. The best way to attract money is to find worthy gaps to fill, the worthiest gaps are the problems people face, and the desires people have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Univers Is Extremely Vast</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-univers-is-extremely-vast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-univers-is-extremely-vast/</guid>
      <description>The Universe is too vast that it encompasses incredibly small like atoms (which forms planets and stars) and the unbelievably gigantic objects (stars, planets, comets), as well as systems/regions of objects (superclusters, black holes, galaxies).
And not only the distances between these objects are beyond our comprehension that we need to use different units of measurement (i.e. astronomical units, light years) other than the ones used on earth.
Temperatures range from near Aabsolute Zero to millions of degrees in the interiors of stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universe Is Extremely Big</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-universe-is-extremely-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-universe-is-extremely-big/</guid>
      <description>On an extremely clear starry night, and assume that you are at somewhere with the best conditions, it&#39;s roughly estimated that we can see between 5,000 and 2,500 stars. It might seem very vast to you, the human, but don&#39;t get fool by your perspective, you&#39;re looking at an EXTREMELY small area of the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wealthy Mind</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-wealthy-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/the-wealthy-mind/</guid>
      <description>The wealthy mind is very different from the working mind. And here&#39;s a list of the differences.
[[Compound Interest]] is a close association of wealth creation. However, it&#39;s often threw around when people use Warren Buffett as a case study, or used by money-making gurus when they are trying to sell courses, but rarely implemented by most people, including these gurus&amp;rsquo; devotees.
[[Work Like Lions, Not Like Gazelles]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There Are No Other Civilizations Out There</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/there-are-no-other-civilizations-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/there-are-no-other-civilizations-out-there/</guid>
      <description>The reason that we haven&#39;t been contacted by extraterrestrial intelligence is because they don&#39;t exist. But since the [[Number of Planets That Possibly Have Life]] suggests that there should be somewhere around 6 billion earth-like planets in our galaxy, if none of them contain life, there must be something prevents life from happening even in the suitable environments.
And this something is the [[Great Filter]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Predators</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/think-like-predators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/think-like-predators/</guid>
      <description>If you watch any wildlife documentary, it&#39;s common that most predators are not on the hunt all the time, let it be lions, tigers, eagles, sharks, etc. Most of the time, they are resting, and playing around.
But on the contrary, ruminants are always eating, or always &amp;ldquo;chewing the cud&amp;rdquo;, in order to have consume the sufficient amount of energy to survive. And these hard working animals are always preyed upon by predators, no exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/thoughts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universe</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/universe/</guid>
      <description>[[The Univers Is Extremely Vast]] for our monkey brains to comprehend so far (AD 2021). You don&#39;t think so, then answer the question: [[Where are the aliens?]]
Not only the space is vast beyond our comprehension, it&#39;s also very lowkey, and isolated from most of what we think about every day. We tend to think Earth is the mother of us humans &amp;amp; everything we observe (which is pretty true), but you need something to make something, and where did mother Earth get all the materials to create us with?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Mostly Stardust</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-mostly-stardust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-mostly-stardust/</guid>
      <description>If you break everything that makes you into the finest small pieces (which means break yourself apart), you&#39;ll end up with various elements.
   Element Symbol Mass Atoms     Oxygen O 65.0% 24.0%   Carbon C 18.5% 12.0%   Hydrogen H 9.5% 62.0%   Nitrogen N 3.2% 1.1%   Total  96.2% 99.1%    To be continued&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are Working Way Too Much</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-working-way-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/we-are-working-way-too-much/</guid>
      <description>As humans, we simply work too much. In my opinion, most people have become the [[The industrialised humans]]. Most of us work like machines and this way of working has been widely accepted as a social norm. Because the societies around the globe have been measuring the quality of the livelihood by GDP for decades, productivity has become the one thing different countries and cities chase after.
In most western countries, people work the standard 9-to-5 days up to 40 hours per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealth</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is extremely important, and not very well understood. And in my opinion, it&#39;s something we all should strive for.
People understand wealth differnetly. To some, making $100,000 a year (in 2020) is considered being rich, having a giant house (without looking at the mortgage and the house owner&#39;s ability to pay it back) represents wealth. But to some, the idea of wealth is drastically different: [[Wealthy People&#39;s Definition of Rich]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealth Is Built Upon Money</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth-is-built-upon-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealth-is-built-upon-money/</guid>
      <description>Wealth need to be built upon money. If you Google the word &amp;ldquo;wealth&amp;rdquo; the dominant explanation is it means financial assets. It&#39;s simply because money has become the glue of society and we&#39;re so dependent on money nowadays. But I do believe that true wealth involves a lot of things beyond money that money can&#39;t buy, like happiness &amp;amp; genuine human relationships. But you&#39;re not gonna be able to fully enjoy these things if money is something you lack of and you have to spend all your time chasing after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealthy People&#39;s Definition of Rich</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealthy-people-s-definition-of-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/wealthy-people-s-definition-of-rich/</guid>
      <description>What&#39;s your definition of Rich?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Are the Aliens?</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/where-are-the-aliens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/where-are-the-aliens/</guid>
      <description>We still don&#39;t know. But we have some assumptions, which helps us to think and prepare for some possibilities.
Famously, The Fermi Paradox address this question.
I wonder, when you look at this starry night sky, what does it make you feel?
When Enrico Fermi saw it, he was like: ”Where is everybody?” His wonders are not irrational, because [[The Universe Is Extremely Big]], and when the numbers get extreme, evem the smallest possibilities would result in some pretty big numbers: [[Number of Planets That Possibly Have Life]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why &#34;My Brain&#34; Is The Best Option I&#39;ve Found So Far</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-my-brain-is-the-best-option-i-ve-found-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/why-my-brain-is-the-best-option-i-ve-found-so-far/</guid>
      <description>The world is complicated, there are tons of ideas require good amount of information to explain, and traditional documents are limited to one linear format to stay relevant to it&#39;s topic, and to explore any other ideas the document mentions, it takes the reader good amount of time &amp;amp; effort to do so.
Not only that, linearity is an idea most people subscribe to, and it&#39;s carved into their hard very deep, that most people treat most things as linear, and linearity makes things seem simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Like Lions, Not Like Gazelles</title>
      <link>https://adamliu.io/blog/work-like-lions-not-like-gazelles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamliu.io/blog/work-like-lions-not-like-gazelles/</guid>
      <description>This idea is closely related to [[Think Like Predators]], and it&#39;s the opposite to the widely accepted social norm: [[We Are Working Way Too Much]].
The money we earn, and the quality of our lives is not defined by the intensity and the hours we work, but rather, it&#39;s defined by the value we provide.
And Value increases &amp;amp; decreases in an exponential manner, not in a linear manner.
If you can provide great value, you should still be rewarded handsomely even if you don&#39;t work for a second.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>